foreign
[Music]
guys let's roll the cameras
we are 13 18 and we are
facing the prospect of stronger
opposition
I'm pretty sure I'm gonna have the black
pieces this time let's jump in another
15 plus 10 speed run game
today
okay we're playing at 1163
so a slightly weaker opponent but
there's nothing wrong with that and that
doesn't mean we can't play an
instructive game
so we start the game with a sicilian as
we've done thus far in the speed run
and at this level we're probably not
going to face
an open Sicilian we're very likely to
face kind of the Italian against the
Sicilian with Bishop C4 or Bishop B5 or
one of those offbeat Sicilians but we
continue down the main path with Knight
to C6 initiating The Accelerated dragon
in the event of D4 we take it and play
G6 and as predicted white plays the move
Bishop C4 now the reason this move is so
popular at
a sort of post beginner level is largely
because players don't study the Sicilian
and they kind of default to the moves
that they make against E5 so if you play
the Italian against D5 you're likely to
play the same moves against the Sicilian
and the reason that Bishop C4 is
ineffective against this particular
setup is very simple and it can be
encapsulated in one word and that word
is well two words E6
right the old the reason you don't put
the bishop on C4 here is because E6
blunts the bishop and then later on D5
could come with Tempo but D5 isn't
altogether necessary what's important is
to realize that E6 completely blunts the
bishop and makes it look kind of dumb
so we start by playing E6 now can you
play G6 here can you play this like you
would an accelerator Dragon absolutely
nothing wrong with the move G6 but we're
gonna play this very thematically and
again I'm trying to be as principled as
possible I'm trying to really punish bad
opening play as much as possible white
plays the move C3 okay so this is kind
of a souped-up elephant
I'm assuming that our opponent is
preparing D4
and here we have
a million ways that we can handle this
position if we want to try to squeeze
the most out of our uh if we want to
really punish white fully for playing
Bishop C4 it makes sense for us to play
the move D5 here and occupy some of the
center especially because that move
occurs with Tempo an interesting
alternative would be to start with
Knight F6 but the drawback of playing
Knight F6 is that E5 is a tad bit
annoying right E5 forces the Knight off
of F6
in the knife to jump for example to G4
but then white attaches uh the pawns
together with D4 and we get into this
kind of weird concrete struggle that
there is absolutely no reason to engage
in if we're playing Black so the
position is not better for black we're
not better here uh but we equalize very
very easily after the straightforward
move D5 which we're gonna play
and we can pre-move e takes D5 but I'm
trying to avoid pre-moves in the speed
run
yeah so D5 is very straightforward we
are getting control of the center and
doing it with tempo
so our opponent's sinking into a bit of
a thing here
and of course white is not strictly
forced to play 865 but there are no
viable Alternatives there we go we have
an exchange of Pawns in the center and
here the order of operations is going to
be pretty important in what order do we
develop our minor pieces and where do we
put them I think a lot of players
actually struggle uh with these types of
positions specifically because you've
got three minor pieces to develop and
it's easy to get overwhelmed uh as to
like which pieces to develop first and
where they should go because they can go
to a lot of different places now we
shouldn't make any hard and fast
decisions until we understand where the
bishop is going because the placement of
the light skirt Bishop is going to
influence our development and there we
have it Bishop B3 is a case in point
against other Bishop moves we would have
been very likely to deploy the dark
squared Bishop to D6 and then move in
the Knight to E7 here we can't do it in
that order because Bishop D6 simply
drops the pawn on D5 right
so you might see well then we should
play the move Bishop to E7 but Bishop B7
is kind of a weird way to start I mean
you're taught to develop Knights before
Bishops I don't think there's anything
inherently wrong with Bishop E7 I just
think it's a lot more natural to start
by developing the G8 Knight now where
should we move it well that's a pretty
obvious question Knight ge7 makes the
least amount of sense of any development
move because it completely blocks in the
dark squared Bishop
right so Knight F6 here seems very
natural and you just you don't need to
ReDiscover the wheel
in these types of positions just bring
your pieces out and put them on normal
squares Knight F6 Bishop B7 castles the
other Bishop can go out to G4
I mean development is an art in some
ways but in other ways it's all about
just like using your common sense okay
C4 and this is of course the first step
in the wrong direction for our opponent
it's a weird move which I think
conceptually our opponent is trying to
contest our control of the center but in
reality
um he's helping he's helping us and it's
it's an incredibly weakening move C4 we
can react to this move in a variety of
ways I think most of you are very
tempted by the move d4
why is the move d4 tempting well in
general it's always tempting to move
upon forward and you might notice that
D4 takes away the C3 Square from White's
Knight so that's a good thing and D4 is
a good move
but there's also a serious case to be
made here
for taking on C4
and you might say I don't like this move
because it plays into White's hands and
it allows white to recapture with the
bishop and open up this diagonal well
the diagonal isn't that important
because after we deploy our Dark Sword
bishop and Castle is white really going
to develop that much pressure on F7 like
white doesn't have any other pieces
developed and the good thing about DC is
that it essentially leaves white with a
very weak backward Pawn on D2
and with the D file open it's going to
be easier in the long run I'm talking
like really long run 10 to 15 moves from
now to put more pressure on the D2 Pawn
it's going to be easier for us to do
that
so D4 is a good move conceptually but it
keeps the center very closed and I'm not
necessarily the biggest fan of that
especially because we're trying to play
in the spirit of the opening and In the
Sicilian we like open Center positions
so we're actually going to make a
decision I think a lot of you might find
questionable and we're going to take on
C4 but hopefully I've explained my logic
well enough and now we're going to bring
out the dark Squad bishop and the reason
we bring out the dark squared Bishop is
because the top priority here should be
to Castle well why should the priority
be to Castle because if you look at
White's development White's next two
moves are very likely to be Castle's
King side and then rookie one check and
we don't want our King stuck in the
center
uh when that Rook moves into E1 we don't
want to have to deal with that so we've
got Bishop E7 and Bishop D6 from the
perspective of activity Bishop D6 is the
more active developing Square they might
see well but Bishop D6 allows white to
push D4 and eradicate the weakness and
this is where you actually just need to
calculate you need to be familiar with
the typical Motif as it turns out Bishop
d64 does not work for white because if
you imagine everything trades on D4 and
then you have Bishop D6 to B4 check a
very common Motif that you have to be
familiar with
uh picking up white screen
so for this reason we're going to bring
our Bishop out to the most active
possible Square
exploiting the fact that white really
can never play D4 and white can't play
D4 even after they Castle
which is very important and for the very
same reason not Bishop B4 check this
time but of course Bishop takes H2 check
in the end
and this is an incredibly common blunder
at this level now our opponent is
playing well D3 is a good move
and here we need to basically combine
development with prophylaxis right
there's two options here that I see for
black the first option is to develop the
bishop to G4 well I cannot draw that
Arrow Bishop G4 the second option A more
prophylactic approach I think Petrosian
would play the second move is to play H6
to stop White's Bishop from coming out
to be equivalent G5 square and I really
like H6 I feel like moves like H6 they
really make it difficult for newer
players to operate when you take away uh
you know their their intentions so let's
throw in the move H6
thank you mail it out for Prime we're
preventing Bishop G5 now some of you
might might be wondering are we not
worried about a sacrifice on H6 right
are we not worried that we're weakening
the king side well the answer is no
because again white barely has any
pieces developed and with our pieces
developed very actively there's just no
reason that this sacrifice is going to
work like Bishop takes H6 here we just
play G takes H6 and we can always bring
the king up to G7 on the next move to
support the H6 Pawn
so of course now we play Bishop G4 all
right so Bishop G4 I'm not even really
explaining were there any other tempting
squares well perhaps you could say the
bishop F5 pressures the pawn on Z3 but I
find the PIN to be a lot more juicy here
especially because
um and and by the way in our previous
Speed Run game in the E4 B6 Speed Run I
discussed this a little bit it's a
situation where white actually can't
easily get rid of the PIN
now if you move the queen you allow
Bishop takes F3 ruining the structure
if the pawn was not on D3 then white
would be able to slide the bishop back
to E2 this is a very common technique
for dealing with pins and it's not the
most active move but it would allow the
Knight to move freely as it stands
there's no Bishop E2 so what are we
threatening here with black we have a
massive positional threat here and
perhaps not even as much a positional
threat as a tactical threat and that is
the typical move Knight C6 to D4
we're threatening to jump into D4 or to
E5 either way
and either way white will be unable to
prevent us from capturing on F3 and
completely ruining White's kingside Pawn
structure which you know I'm sure you've
seen or you've had your share of games
where this happens and once the pawn
structure is ruined like that on the
same side in which you're castled couple
that with the fact that our dark squared
Bishop is aiming right at H2 and the
attack is just going to be blistering
and it's going to be unstoppable and our
opponent has just allowed it he's played
Queen B3 and without a second thought we
snapped that Knight off the board
but we're gonna have to think carefully
after white recaptures because it's not
actually that easy to figure out a path
forward our opponent is thinking
so maybe our opponent has realized that
you know G takes F3 is is a massive
concession and let's see if he maybe
just panics and does something crazy
like not recapture the piece which you
sometimes see of course white should
recapture it I mean everything else just
loses on the spot
now start thinking about what we're
going to do after G takes after because
I think we can procrastinate a little
bit on the more general question of how
we're going to attack there is a move
that we can make here that's most
definitely not going to hurt we know for
a fact that this move is not going to
hurt now which move am I talking about
I'm talking about the move Knight C6 to
D4 and it's important to point out that
if white captures the pawn on p7 first
of all we don't really give a damn about
Pawns in a position like this we're
playing for checkmate but more
specifically after Queen takes B7 notice
that you have the move Rook A8 to B8
okay that dislodges the queen and forces
it to lose contact with the F3 Pawn
because all of the squares on that
diagonal are defended by our Knights
so after Knight T4 Queen takes B7 Rook
B8 Queen takes A7 we capture the pawn on
F3 with a check and then we can follow
up sorry about that and then we can
follow up
by taking also the pawn on H2 just fully
uh you know disrobing the white king and
that just looks super juicy we don't
have to calculate any further and so
Knight T4 is a fully Justified move
and in a classical game I really
wouldn't even calculate past Queen B7
Rook B8
denuding denuding I think is a better
word than disrobing although I'm
kind of happy with my choice of words
there as well
so I really wouldn't calculate past
Queen takes B7 Rook B8 because worse
comes to worst were down upon and the
pawn on F3 is one of the only pawns that
protects White's King if that pawn
disappears then the floodgates
essentially open now you might be like
well what's the pawn on F3 actually
doing well for one thing it's protecting
the G4 square if the pawn wasn't there
we'd have a Greek gift sacrifice
actually and we'd also have Knight F6 to
G4 followed by Queen H4 so the pawn is
making it a little bit difficult for us
uh to to worm our way toward the king
side and that's why white has to play
Queen B3 back to D1 that's the only move
to keep the pawn on F3 protected and
again start thinking
about what our next move is going to be
after Queen D1 and if white plays Queen
takes B7 that'll be a pleasant surprise
and then everything's gonna be really
easy
so let's start discussing what our
attacking techniques are going to be
here
and what move we're going to make
because it's not easy to find an
accurate move after Queen D1 so looking
at this first of all from a broad
standpoint what is it that we want on
the king side what is our goal well well
our goal is pretty easy to figure out
our goal is to bring our Queen into the
attack it's going to be hard to
Checkmate white just with our minor
pieces we need to bring our Queen
ideally to one of two squares either H3
or H4 if the queen lands on either of
these squares it's going to generate
potentially Unstoppable mating threats
H3 is really the golden Square that's
the square we really want to get that's
like boardwalk and Monopoly right H4 is
like Park Place but there's a couple of
squares that we might also compromise on
right what about H5 right or or F5 okay
well this is where unfortunately newer
players like I said again and again we
put a lot of pressure on them and they
tend to panic in in ways that you know
sometimes make you laugh but you know
everybody is like that when they're
still new to the game they're just not
used to managing that amount of pressure
Bishop F7 is a is a flat out blunder we
just play Rook takes F7 and this
actually makes things worse for white on
the king side because now The Rook aims
at the F3 Pawn so once we move the
Knight away from F6 not only does it
create the threat of Queen H4 but it
also threatens the pawn on F3 and that
pawn can hardly be defended so the game
is already over
they are there the game is already over
and after the game
we'll discuss a little bit more at
length what uh we would have done
against the more resilient Queen D1 okay
so here we can win in literally A
Million Ways the the simplest move the
business-like move is Knight takes F3
check
but that actually might not be the best
move which is I know a really weird
thing to say but remember our ultimate
goal is to get the queen into the attack
which Square in particular well H3 if we
can make that happen so just applying
simple logic what seems to be a move
that we at least have to consider yeah
well Queen D7 right Queen D7 is not
fancy it's a utilitarian move but it's
incredibly powerful
so after Queen D7 White's response is
forced the only way that white can
prevent Queen H3 is by playing King G2
but after King G2 notice that the F3
Pawn becomes even more of a liability
because if we capture it with our Queen
we capture it with check so after Queen
D7 King G2
we basically settle for a square that's
almost as good as H3 we play the move
what move do we play figure it out
Queen D7 King G2 and this might very
well happen in the game
who can spot the move very good Queen D7
to F5 simple chess and the pawn on F3
simply cannot be defended we just take
on F3 and we made him notice that Queen
D5 doesn't work because the Knight is
still on F6 and it defends D5 we we've
managed to do this without moving the
Knight away which would have also been
possible we could have played
even a retreating move like Knight D7
would have been
tremendously powerful here some of you
are suggesting some fancy moves Knight
G4 a sack on H2 and all of that is
totally unnecessary uh if we can play
this uh in a more simple way so Queen D7
I really like
and I will remind you at this point that
when you're like up a piece and you're
mating your opponent there's going to be
like seven or eight winning options in
many cases on every move and you
shouldn't you know you shouldn't
have the mentality that oh I was coming
up with a different move and Daniel
played this movement so my move is
terrible not necessarily right your move
may have been an alternative now what's
the clinical way to Checkmate the white
king here there's an order of operations
that has to be adhered to remember our
ultimate goal is to put the queen on H3
so we can start with a move Queen H3 and
you'll notice that that threatens Knight
F3 and queen takes H2 with Checkmate but
if you have a set of two moves you
should always test the other move order
I mean you should do it as a habit and
it's easy to establish here in our
opponent resides that Knight F3 check is
actually the more accurate move order
and I wasn't trying to taunt our
opponent I was just trying to spell it
out Knight F3 check is the actual forced
mate because after King G2 we throw in
the preliminary check on G4 driving the
king back and then we play Queen H3 with
of course the Unstoppable mating
construction technically if you start
with Queen H3 white can Stave off
checkmate with the move F2 F3 and of
course now The Rook defends the pawn you
would still be completely winning here
obviously but Knight F3 is forced mate
simple game we'll play another one
but let's go over a couple of the the
key points and I'll talk a little bit
about opening Theory as well so what's
funny is when I did my lessons with
Charlie and those of you watching on
YouTube who don't you know for whom
Charlie does not ring a bell Charlie
refers to moist critical uh that's his
sort of YouTube and twitch name
he is a very popular YouTuber of
millions of subs and I coached him for
the chess.com POG gems tournament so all
of my lessons with them are available on
YouTube on my on my YouTube channel you
can check it out and I was teaching
Charlie The Accelerated dragon
and most of his opponents ended up
playing the move Bishop C4 so we
actually talked a lot about the theory
of Bishop C4 even though there's really
no commonly accepted Theory this move is
simply bad so it's not like you'll find
a lot of stuff in books about this move
but it's it's bad not in the sense that
black is better it's bad in the sense
that it doesn't fight for an advantage
if that makes sense so he played E6 and
I don't actually think the move C3 isn't
all that bad either
uh the main line in so far as we can
call this a main line is after White
Castles kingside this is what most
people play what I thought Charlie was a
really interesting idea that involves
playing Knight F6
now why does a couple of moves in this
position we'll look at three we'll look
at D3 to defend the pawn
rookie one to defend the Pawn With The
Rook we're actually gonna look at four
moves Knight C3 developing the Knight
and finally the topical move the
principled move is of course E5
okay so after rookie one
uh there is a very nice trick that gives
black a super comfortable position who
can find this trick and I'm going to
keep this deliberately vague what does
trick mean well you figure it out what
does black do
yeah it's the center fork trick I think
the official name for it is the center
fork trick
and it should ring a bell immediately
now Knight takes C4 this occurs in a
million different ways it wears a bunch
of different clothes but it's the same
exact tactic anytime there's a bishop on
C4 C5 you take the pawn in the center
and then Fork the resulting two pieces
with your pawn and the point of this
exchange is not that it wins material it
doesn't white can give up the bishop
back for the pawn but black gets the
bishop pair and a Tempo move
and here white also gets a Tempo move
Knight C3
but according to my analysis the queen
should jump over to F5 it's kind of a
nice little square where the queen
actually can't really be attacked and
white can equalize here but he needs to
be very careful black is very much in
the driver's seat with a bishop pair uh
the engine line is I mean most people
here I think would play D3 and after
Bishop E7 black is already better the
engine line is D4 and then black is
supposed to trade on D4 so takes takes
takes takes of course there's the threat
of a rook dhx so we play Bishop E7 and
again black is incredibly comfortable
here given time we're gonna castle and
then fee and Kettle the light score
bishop and amen at the king
and uh you know in order to keep
equality of the end the engine
recommends the Roka four Queen E5 rookie
four queen of five with a repetition but
again it's one of those things like
nobody's actually going to find all of
these moves so this is the most clinical
line so that's rookie one
now D3 of course avoids the center for
trick Knight takes C4 makes no sense
here on the other hand D3 allows us to
play once again the move D5 much like in
the game
and after the trade white should
probably put the bishop on B5 to at
least create some pressure against the
Knight and here a great example of
adapting your development to what's
going on in the board you can play
Bishop D6 but I prefer the simpler move
Bishop E7 to take the sting out of the
check on E1 so after Bishop E7 if white
plays the menacing looking 95 this is
not dangerous at all we just play Queen
C7
and again it looks very menacing after
Bishop F4 but if you look carefully
black has the simple Bishop E7 to D6
and White's quote-unquote initiative
Fizzles out after Knight C6 Bishop F4
there's actually no good discover check
and black is nearly winning
it's kind of a cool line
if you just look at this carefully
you'll see that the Knight is no good
squares if Knight takes A7 check we
simply Play Bishop t7 and the Knight is
trapped the Knight is literally just
trapped in this line yeah white can give
a check big deal we just go King f8
don't be afraid to move your king to the
side like that it should never it's
never as big of a deal as you might
think it is
so this is kind of a cool line but I'm
getting really bugged bogged down into
the details of course if white doesn't
play 95 then black castles and is very
comfortable
so next line is Knight C3
and Knight C3 is just another way to
defend E4 and this allows once again the
center fork trick in an even better
version 94 94 D5
and if black plays Bishop to D3 this is
perhaps the only thing that you have to
memorize out of this entire analysis
here and I'll show you guys a very
interesting parallel to a different line
what is Black's move in this position
and the fact that I'm already asking you
that question should give you a major
hint about what it's not who can find
this move I'll be impressed
it's not an easy move to understand well
it kind of is actually if you think
about it
it is C4 very nice so you make the
intermezzo
you attack the bishop
and the point of this move is simple if
the bishop moves back to E2 well then
you play D takes E4 and you're simply up
a pawn right okay
well is there anything else though I can
do well white can try to play Bishop
takes E4 and give the bishop up for uh
for the pawn and in this case it's best
to actually take the Knight although
taking the bishop is also okay because
this sends the Knight back to E1 that's
a ridiculously passive square and after
Bishop D6 D3 we can just continue
developing and black is much better
notice that white pays the price for the
placement of this Knight D takes E4 runs
into Bishop takes H2 and the queen is
lost because there's no contact between
the rook and the Queen
so at any rate all of these moves are
very subpar and E5 is also subparts just
when most people play and here the
Knight jumps into G4 attacking the pawn
from the other side
and when white plays rookie one black
breaks up the pawn with the simple move
D6 this is what I showed Charlie e takes
d6's forced we play Bishop takes D6 and
for example after H3 Knight G goes back
to E5 and black has a very comfortable
position we have better control of the
center excellent minor pieces and after
Bishop B5 we just play Bishop D7 and
these lines I'm going through very fast
because they're simple they're easy to
follow and I will conclude this little
opening overview with one beautiful
trick if white tries to break free in
the center with D4 who can tell me the
winning line after CD Queen takes D4 and
if you're tactically sharp you should
find this almost instantly you should
you should identify the theme
immediately and it might take you a
second to figure out the logistics of it
very good knight F3 preliminary move to
open up the bishop
and after gf3 we throw in another check
on H2 winning the queen
yeah opponents hate this one simple
trick so hopefully everything made sense
here again the point of the speed run
this is an opening theme speedrun so I
am going to do a good amount of this
type of opening analysis I hope it's not
too dry
um I am really trying to help people
learn a full repertoire like my goal is
that by the end of the speedrun you will
have if you watch it diligently and you
supplement it with your own learning
you're going to have a full opening
repertoire that you can just apply right
this is for people who just are kind of
looking to start from scratch and kind
of want guidance about what to play
so yes you know there's going to be a
fair amount of dry opening analysis and
I deviate from a lot of other coaches in
that I tell my students that you have to
do a rather uh substantial amount of
memorization even as a beginner if you
really want to learn openings properly I
hate the whole idea which is spread by a
lot of you know chess authors and
coaches that like oh there's a way to
learn openings where you don't have to
memorize a single line when you're a
beginner you should stay away from
memorization BS there's a fear of
memorization among like the opening
levels which which you shouldn't have
you really should try to memorize a good
amount of theory now you can memorize
and understand at the same time you can
memorize the move but also understand
why it's played right so Knight F6 you
can remember this move but say hey I get
why this move is made we're trying to
orchestrate the center fork trick with
Knight takes C4 so a little bit of a
tangent but remember that it's okay to
learn opening files with the aim of
memorizing moves some moves some just
have to be memorized
um so you're trying to strike the
balance between the two
um the ideas behind the moves are also
very important so hopefully this made
sense we go back to this position move
four our opponent plays a very rare move
and allows us to immediately strike in
the center with with D5 so already we've
solved all of our opening problems and I
think black is the only one who can
realistically be better here
so takes takes Bishop back to B3 uh
Bishop Bishop B5 is is what I expected
uh and here we were planning to play
Bishop D6 uh castles and like I
mentioned the Knight very often comes
out to E7 in order to take the sting out
of this bishop
and to take this thing out of the check
and this is a very sort of compact uh
form of development Black's got a great
position I forgot to mention one thing I
mentioned that I'd show you a parallel
uh with this C4 move that we just looked
at so in the English in the in the four
nights English there is a line
which I often play in Blitz E2 E4 and
black responds with Bishop C5 white
initiates the center fork trick with
Knight 65.
and a ton of players including a ton of
grand Masters in this position play the
erroneous Bishop back to D6 this is
ridiculously common and what's amazing
is that White's already winning after
the next move and I won't ask you for
the next move hopefully you've been
paying attention the move is not D take
C5 but rather C5 it's the same exact
concept what Black's position just falls
apart either you drop the bishop and
your Pawn structures ruined or you have
to move the bishop in your knight has to
go back to G8 and this really deserves
no further comment after Bishop C4 and
like Queen D5 the game is already over
I've won a ton of games like this
so another idea to file into your mental
Rolodex but in any case white plays
Bishop B3 so here we amend our opening
strategy with Knight F6 and C4 is
definitely a a very weird move it's not
a terrible move but it we're very much
spoiled for Choice after this move so a
lot of you here were proposing this move
Queen E7 check which honestly I didn't
even consider I I can see that it's the
top engine move I do see that uh but
this is this is a bit of a weird move
and the reason I didn't consider it is
because of Queen E2 I figured a queen
trade isn't really in Black's favor and
I guess I'm wrong and the reason I'm
wrong is for very concrete reasons
because after the queen trade black has
an absolutely devastating move and this
is a development move but it it leads to
an initiative that uh bases itself on
the weakness of the D4 square and the
fact that white so undeveloped what's
this move what move am I referring to
here
yeah it's just Bishop C8 to G4 and it's
a very simple move and after C takes D5
Knight D4 check White's position just
crumbles it falls apart you have nowhere
good to go with your king king F1 is
forced and after Knight takes B3 a b
Knight T5 just look at White's Pawn
structure look at White's weak squares
we can also take on F3 it's like minus
three so this would in fact have been
the most effective way to punish C4
the queen E7 white can also play King F1
of course
but then then we'll take and we'll get
the bishop out and we'll castle
queenside and we'll have another like
raging initiative against black White's
King so that doesn't solve any problems
either we played DC and Bishop D6 which
I would argue is a very uh
straightforward and simple way to gain
the advantage
so after Bishop D6 castles castles let
me just reiterate that D4 in this
position would have in fact solved all
of White's problems were it not for the
very concrete trick Bishop takes H2 and
if you're a beginner against a very
important idea just to remember
and so our opponent plays D3
and here we decided on the simple H6 to
prevent Bishop G5 white plays Knight C3
and frankly I think Knight C3 might be
the decisive mistake I think this move
already allows an Unstoppable problem of
Knight D4 and Bishop takes F3
so the reality is that white had to play
H3 here to stay in the game
but after Bishop F5 Black's Advantage is
long-term and it's indisputable it's I
mean White's position is really
miserable with his backward Pawn on D3
and let's say white plays Knight C3
black is a lot of possibilities I like
the move Queen D7 trying to sack on H3
and for us the sacrifice is a lot more
realistic because we've got other pieces
aiming at the king side
um so my name is Chico asks a question
about a little bit earlier let me rewind
so my name is Suga you're asking about
D4 but remember that in this position
there is a bishop on C4 that's blocking
the Queen's access to that square you
were saying why not Bishop B4 Chuck
Queen takes before it's because this
bishop is in the way okay so once I
played these moves on the board you
should see that
all right
but good to clarify so after Bishop G4
already White's position is dire and I
should point out that after H3 Bishop H5
G4
which would be a a typical way of
dealing with the spin we automatically
and here really automatically take on G4
here the sacrifice should be totally
automatic for you because you already
know that black has the Unstoppable twin
threats of Knight T4 and 95 you can stop
one of them but not both you can play
Bishop E3 or you can play rookie one but
in either case we put the Knight on just
the other square and we either win the
Knight on F3 with mate or we win the
queen on D1 so it's just very obvious
that there's no defense here and I don't
know what white should have done but I
think the position is nearly hopeless
this makes it even worse we take it we
go Knight T4 and the last point of
discussion is what would we have done
after Queen to D1
again many paths lead to Rome here but
the move that I was planning is actually
not Queen D7 so here the circumstances
have changed after Queen D7 King G2
remember that in the game we had this
move Queen F5 now we can still play this
but we're not attacking F3 anymore so
it's not quite as effective and white
has a Tempo to bring in defensive forces
which can really douse the Flames of the
attack pretty quickly so I think the
best move is to take a slightly
different path and go Knight H5
now the thread is Queen H4 and the
obvious defensive move here is 94. but I
think a crucial point is that we can
play Queen H4 anyway
now this seems to drop a bishop but who
can tell me what the subtlety is how
does black proceed in this position
and having familiarized yourself with
all of the attacking ideas this should
be really easy
so where does black go if you're on
YouTube obviously pause figure it out
so it's not Knight F4 because of just
Bishop takes F4
yeah you're attracted to this maid
threat but you're forgetting the bishop
can just take the Knight
so the move is Queen H3
it's subtle and it's deadly it threatens
Knight takes F3 right that makes sense
white has to play Bishop D5 but now
these pieces are
aligned chess is insane and we just go
Rook 88 and we win back at least one of
the pieces but more importantly this is
just a rook lift like the point is not
to take the Knight the point is to go to
G6 and just check me at the white king
notice that Bishop F4 here not possible
because of the Knight on H5 so that's
actually why we need the Knight there to
control the F4 Square
but you can also do this intuitive you
don't have to see that to play Knight H5
it's clear that we want the Knight
somewhere on the king side
okay so this is virtually forced the
engine moves F4
and here even better than Knight takes
F4 is just to bring the queen in anyway
and it's like minus four I mean we're
about to take on F4 That's All She Wrote
so Queen D1 would not have saved white
but our opponent gives up the piece and
allows uh immediate immediate Checkmate
I remind you that the move here is
Knight F3 check and then Queen G4 Queen
H3 as necessary with mate so a simple
game a straightforward game but I
thought we had a fruitful discussion of
the uh the sort of Sicilian or Italian
against the Sicilian line and uh you
basically never have to learn it again
if you just remember a couple of these
lines
[Music]